inspire.com 2019-11-02

# Privacy Statement - Inspire

Welcome to Inspire, an online community website ("Site"), and thank you for reviewing this Privacy Statement (the "Statement"). This Site is operated by ClinicaHealth, Inc. dba Inspire and is designed to connect persons (such as those with certain health conditions, caregivers, and professionals) who are interested in sharing and receiving information regarding various health conditions (the "Service").

In connection with the use of this Site and the Service, users may be asked to provide personal information relating to health conditions, demographics, contact information, and other information. This Statement informs you of our practices with respect to the online collection, use, and disclosure of personal information by means of the Service. We reserve the right to change, modify, add, or remove provisions of this Statement, and any changes to this Statement will be posted here.

Please refer back to this Statement regularly because your use of this Site signifies that you agree to be bound by this Statement, as might be amended from time to time.

**What Information About You Do We Collect?**

You may view some content on this Site without becoming a member of Inspire (a "Member"). For example, you may review blogs and discussions written by registered users of the Site. However, you must register in order to post a profile, submit items for discussion, write a blog, write comments about discussion entries and blog entries, post a message, or communicate with others via the Service. At the registration page, you are asked to provide certain personal information, including a functioning e-mail address at which we may contact you, your location, your gender, and your date of birth. Upon registering, you become a Member.

You have the option to provide additional personal information, for example, to create an extended online profile. In addition, it is possible for you to provide personal information about yourself when you post content on the Service or communicate with other registered Members.

We also collect "clickstream" data, including your IP address and what pages you visit on the Site, so we can monitor and improve the performance of the Site and Service and learn how different aspects of the Site and Service are used.

**What We Do With Your Personal Information**

We use personal information that you provide to us in several ways.

First, we use it to confirm your membership, and to understand better who is visiting our Site and using our Service, to help us improve the Service and present content which better suits your interests.

Second, we may use the personal information you give us to send you information about Inspire and the Service, as well as material on behalf of third parties with whom we have a business relationship. By third parties we mean, for example, entities such as health associations and advertisers that link to our Site or that make use of our Service. The information we send you may, on occasion, contain advertising or requests either from us or from a third party on whose behalf we would send the information. For example, we may contact you to see whether you are interested in being considered for an upcoming clinical trial that is being sponsored by a pharmaceutical company. Clicking on links to third party websites or enabling connections with third parties may allow those third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third party websites and are not responsible for their privacy policies. When you leave our Site, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit. Please remember that their use of your personal information will be governed by their privacy policies and terms.

Third, when you register for the Service, your profile becomes visible to users of the Service and your profile may be found by users of the Service. You can control how your profile and the data it contains are shared on the Site by using the privacy settings available to you in the account settings section of the Site. Additionally, when you post information on the Site forums, such as by creating or replying to journal entries, discussions or messages, that information is considered to have been publicly disclosed by you and is no longer considered personal information for purposes of this Statement.

Fourth, we may share personal information with entities that are not part of the Inspire family, including technical infrastructure service providers and academic researchers, on an aggregate basis. These entities are required to adhere to strict confidentiality and data security requirements consistent with this Statement and our specific agreements with them.

Fifth, Inspire may disclose personal information that you give us to appropriate persons in circumstances where we have a good faith belief that a user is likely to cause bodily harm to themselves or others.

Sixth, Inspire may share your email address and profile information with the organizations (for example, non-profit organizations) that sponsor Inspire communities that you join.

Otherwise, we do not share, sell, or otherwise disclose individually identifiable personal information to any entity that we do not control, without your prior consent, except as required by law. For example, we do not sell our Member lists to other entities; however, we may provide them with aggregate data about our Members in support of medical research that does not contain contact or other individually identifiable personal information. Examples of such aggregate data include counts of Members belonging to a specific community or in a particular geographic region.

**Your Choices**

You are not required to provide any personal information in order to view information that appears on this Site. However, in order to post content or see profiles of Members or communicate with Members, you must register. When you register, you must provide the personal information designated as "required" on the registration page. After you have registered, you will have the opportunity to provide additional personal information and to create an extended personal profile, including the posting of a photograph. Whether you provide this additional personal information is entirely your option, although it may affect your full enjoyment of the Service.

If you do not wish us to use or disclose personal information that you provide through this Site as disclosed in this Statement, you should not create an Inspire account, or if you already have an Inspire account, you should deactivate your membership, as described in the "Deactivating Your Membership" section.

**Deactivating Your Membership**

If at any time you decide that you want us to stop processing your information, you should deactivate your membership, and optionally indicate if you desire the removal of all of your posts and replies. You can deactivate your membership two different ways:

  * Send an email to team@inspire.com expressing your wishes, or
  * Use the "Permanently close account" function on the Site.

**Public Forums**

This Site may make available chat rooms, blogs, and message boards. Please remember that any personal or other information that you disclose in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

**Access**

You may access and change personal information on your profile at any time by accessing your password-protected registered user information.

**Protecting Your Data**

Stewardship of your personal information is critical to us and a responsibility we embrace. We have a team dedicated to keeping your information secure including testing for vulnerabilities. We also have established internal policies and procedures to limit access to Members' personal information to only those employees who need the information to perform a specific job.

We only process personal information where we have a legal basis for doing so. We review the personal information we hold on a regular basis to ensure it is being lawfully processed and that it is accurate, relevant, and up to date. Before transferring personal information to any third party (e.g. suppliers, partners, customers, software solution providers, and back office support), we establish that there is a legal reason for making the transfer, which may include your consent.

Inspire employs commercially reasonable security measures consistent with standard industry practice, to safeguard personal and other information collected through this Site. We believe these commercially reasonable practices provide adequate security to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of the information we collect on our Site. We have implemented measures and procedures that adequately protect the privacy of individuals and ensure that data protection is integral to all processing activities. This includes implementing measures such as:

  * Data minimization (e.g. not keeping data for longer than is necessary);
  * Pseudonymization;
  * Anonymization;
  * Cyber security; and
  * A data security policy.

We will only retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes for which we process your personal information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

**Minimum Age Requirement**

Consistent with various regulations, you must be at least 16 years old to join Inspire.

**Cookies**

We use a standard technology called "cookies", as well as Google Analytics and Segment to collect information about how you use the Site and to help us administer the Site. Some cookies reside on your computer persistently and help our Site to recognize your computer's browser as a previous visitor. We also use "session cookies" which expire when you close your browser and do not retain any information about you after they expire. This information allows us to customize delivery of information. For example, our Site may use cookies to save and remember registration information or preferences that you may have set while browsing the Site, to ensure you don't see the same ad content repeatedly, and to deliver content specific to your interests. We use cookies only to gather information as indicated in this Statement. Inspire currently does not respond to Do Not Track requests.

**Advertising**

Inspire uses advertising to promote Inspire elsewhere on the Internet, and in other places. In some cases, we use technologies to track and understand what happens after someone sees, or clicks on, an advertisement for Inspire. We use these technologies to measure the effectiveness of our advertising. In particular, we use the conversion tracking feature of Google AdWords to measure the effectiveness of AdWords advertisements in bringing new members to Inspire. You can request more detail about this topic by sending an e-mail to team@inspire.com.

**Banner Advertising**

We allow another company to serve advertisements on our Site. That company may set "cookies" on your computer. We will not share any individually identifiable personal information that you provide to us with such advertising company, and it will not have access to your personal profile. However, it is possible that such advertising company may, through your use of this Site and other websites, develop its own separate profile of you. Any information collected or stored by the ad-service or the cookies is subject to the terms and policies of that company.

**Your Privacy Rights**

**We believe in Trust and Transparency and therefore the data rights set forth in the GDPR apply to all of our members. All members have the right to transparency, access, correct, restrict, or erase their personal information stored on our platform at any time.**

You can also exercise any of these rights at any time by contacting us at [team@inspire.com]. Your data rights include the following:

  * _Accessing your data._ Upon request, we shall provide any information relating to your data and our processing of your data in a concise, transparent, intelligible, and easily accessible form using clear and plain language. The information shall be provided in writing or by other means, including, where appropriate, by electronic means within 30 days of a written request.
  * _Correcting your data._ You have the right to ask us to rectify any inaccurate or incomplete personal information on our platform. If we have given your personal information to any third parties, we will notify those third parties that we have received a request to rectify your personal information, unless doing so proves impossible or involves disproportionate effort. Those third parties should also rectify the personal information they hold - however, we are not in a position to audit those third parties to ensure that the rectification has occurred.
  * _Erasing your data._ You can ask us to erase your personal information stored on our platform. If we receive a request to erase your data, we will ask you if you want your personal information to be removed entirely or if you want to be kept on a list of individuals who do not want to be contacted in the future (for a specified period or otherwise). We cannot keep a record of individuals whose data we have erased so you may be contacted again by us, should we come into possession of your personal information at a later date. If we have given your personal information to any third parties, we will tell those third parties that Inspire has received a request to erase your personal information, unless this proves impossible or involves a disproportionate effort. Those third parties should also rectify the personal information they hold - however, Inspire will not be in a position to audit those third parties to ensure that the rectification has occurred.
  * _Restricting the use of your data._ We only process your personal information where we have the legal basis for doing so. You have the right to ask us to suspend or otherwise restrict the processing of your personal information where: 
    * You challenge the accuracy of the personal information;
    * We no longer need the personal information for the purposes of the processing, but you want us to hold it as you need it to establish, exercise, or defend legal claims; or
    * You have objected to our use of your data, but we need to verify whether we have legitimate grounds to use it.
If we have given the personal information to any third parties, we will tell those third parties that we have received a request to restrict the use of your personal information, unless this proves impossible or involves a disproportionate effort. Those third parties should also rectify the personal information they hold - however, we will not be in a position to audit those third parties to ensure that the rectification has occurred.
  * _Withdrawing your consent._ Where we are relying on consent to process your personal information (for example consent to receive marketing) you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

_A Record of Data Transfer._ Inspire will provide the right to request and receive, once a year and free of charge, information about third parties to whom we have disclosed certain types of personal information (if any) about you for our direct marketing purposes in the prior calendar year, and a description of the categories of personal information shared. To make such a request, please send an email to [team@inspire.com] and please include the phrase "Personal Information Privacy Request" in the subject line, the domain name of the website you are inquiring about, along with your name, address and email address. At our option, we may respond to such requests by providing instructions about how our users can exercise their options to prevent our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

_California Online Privacy Protection Act._ As required by the California Online Privacy Protection Act ("California Act") and the California Business and Professions Code, this Privacy Statement identifies the categories of Personally Identifiable Information (as that term is defined above and in the California Act) that we collect through our website about individual consumers who use or visit our website and the categories of third-party persons or entities with whom such personally identifiable information may be shared. See more about the California Act at http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

**Where We Store and Transfer Your Data**

The EU and the United States. We have users all over the world but to provide you with the Service, we store, use and transmit information only in the United States.

In relation to personal information of individuals in the European Union, we may share your personal information within the Company. This may involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area (the "EEA"). We may also share your data with trusted third parties who assist us in providing, improving, protecting and promoting our Services and this may also involve transferring your data outside the EEA. Whenever we transfer your personal information outside the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it as would be provided in the EEA.

**Sale or Merger**

If Inspire is sold to or merges with another company not owned by Inspire, you should expect that some or all of the personal information collected from this Site may be transferred to the buyer/surviving company. If so, Inspire will seek to obligate the acquiring company to use any personal information transferred by this Site in a manner consistent with this Statement, but cannot guarantee that it will be able to impose that requirement, or that the acquiring company will comply.

If you do not wish the personal information you provide to be subject to this possibility, you should deactivate your membership, as described in the "Deactivating Your Membership" section.

**Legal Process**

You should be aware that Inspire may be required to disclose your personal information to the government or other entities in connection with a legal process, such as in response to a valid subpoena, court order in judicial or regulatory proceedings, or pursuant to a valid law enforcement investigative demand.

**Governing Law**

Any dispute which may arise over privacy will be subject to this Statement and the provisions of law of the State of Delaware.

**Contacting the Service**

If you have any questions about this Statement, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, you can contact team@inspire.com.

**Effective Date**

This Statement is effective as of March 8, 2019.
